<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Review Reminder Action/Shortcut</title>
    <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/project-review-reminder-action-shortcut/9813</link>
    <description>I am using Drafts as my master project list where I keep all of the details around a project. I&#39;ve tried using all the various task management tools, but I find them more useful for specific actions, not project management. While OmniFocus, Things 3 all all good things, I like the freedom that Drafts provides me.

What Drafts doesn&#39;t provide is a review reminder to make sure I don&#39;t have things slipping through the cracks. This is where Reminders (or in my case, Goodtask) excels, reminding me to go review a specific project (Draft). This is done with an Action and a Shortcut.

The Drafts Action is simple, just execute shortcut &quot;Create Project Reminder Review&quot; and pass it the following:

[[title]]
[[uuid]]

(This can be seen here: [Drafts Action Example](https://imgur.com/gallery/JEdaUmm))

The shortcut can be found here: [Create Project Reminder Review](https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/48f68e41863f435e84fa586597909b51)

Note: I used Shortcuts to take advantage of Toolbox Pro (Required) with the ability to add a recurring reminder. I have not found a way to do that totally within Drafts as of yet.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 17:16:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Actions - Share What You&#39;ve Made</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/project-review-reminder-action-shortcut/9813.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Project Review Reminder Action/Shortcut</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Denrael]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I am using Drafts as my master project list where I keep all of the details around a project. I’ve tried using all the various task management tools, but I find them more useful for specific actions, not project management. While OmniFocus, Things 3 all all good things, I like the freedom that Drafts provides me.</p>
<p>What Drafts doesn’t provide is a review reminder to make sure I don’t have things slipping through the cracks. This is where Reminders (or in my case, Goodtask) excels, reminding me to go review a specific project (Draft). This is done with an Action and a Shortcut.</p>
<p>The Drafts Action is simple, just execute shortcut “Create Project Reminder Review” and pass it the following:</p>
<p>[[title]]<br>
[[uuid]]</p>
<p>(This can be seen here: <a href="https://imgur.com/gallery/JEdaUmm" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Drafts Action Example</a>)</p>
<p>The shortcut can be found here: <a href="https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/48f68e41863f435e84fa586597909b51" rel="noopener nofollow ugc">Create Project Reminder Review</a></p>
<p>Note: I used Shortcuts to take advantage of Toolbox Pro (Required) with the ability to add a recurring reminder. I have not found a way to do that totally within Drafts as of yet.</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/project-review-reminder-action-shortcut/9813/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/project-review-reminder-action-shortcut/9813/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 17:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-9813-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/project-review-reminder-action-shortcut/9813.rss">Project Review Reminder Action/Shortcut</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
