<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Append to Evernote Journal action with 2 Evernote accounts</title>
    <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/append-to-evernote-journal-action-with-2-evernote-accounts/12451</link>
    <description>Forgive this post if this has been answered elsewhere. I&#39;ve been using the &quot;Append to Evernote Journal&quot; action which seems to work well. I have 2 Evernote accounts however and would like to have the action in Drafts twice so that I can send different items to each Evernote account. I saw some things online about changing the &quot;credentials&quot; but have been unable to locate that option. Does anyone know of a way to set this action (or a similar one) up and be able to direct it to different accounts in Evernote?</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:44:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Actions - Help &amp; Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/append-to-evernote-journal-action-with-2-evernote-accounts/12451.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Append to Evernote Journal action with 2 Evernote accounts</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[agiletortoise]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Evernote is the one service available in Drafts that does <em>not</em> support multiple accounts.</p>
<p>Evernote’s integration story is a bit of a mess, frankly. I’ve tried to document some of that in the <a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/using-evernote-with-drafts/21">Evernote integration guide</a>.</p>
<p>The direct integration only still works because I have forked their no-longer-supported integration SDK for iOS, does not work on Mac, and does not support some Evernote accounts (like ones which use Google for login) because of issues at Evernote’s end.</p>
<p>Hopefully they will migration to an industry standard REST API at some time in the future and integration can be on-par with other services, but until such a time, it’s pretty limited.</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/append-to-evernote-journal-action-with-2-evernote-accounts/12451/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/append-to-evernote-journal-action-with-2-evernote-accounts/12451/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-12451-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/append-to-evernote-journal-action-with-2-evernote-accounts/12451.rss">Append to Evernote Journal action with 2 Evernote accounts</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Append to Evernote Journal action with 2 Evernote accounts</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[sb1317z]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Forgive this post if this has been answered elsewhere. I’ve been using the “Append to Evernote Journal” action which seems to work well. I have 2 Evernote accounts however and would like to have the action in Drafts twice so that I can send different items to each Evernote account. I saw some things online about changing the “credentials” but have been unable to locate that option. Does anyone know of a way to set this action (or a similar one) up and be able to direct it to different accounts in Evernote?</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/append-to-evernote-journal-action-with-2-evernote-accounts/12451/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/append-to-evernote-journal-action-with-2-evernote-accounts/12451/1</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 14:46:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-12451-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/append-to-evernote-journal-action-with-2-evernote-accounts/12451.rss">Append to Evernote Journal action with 2 Evernote accounts</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
