<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Easier access to basic actions in MacOS</title>
    <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445</link>
    <description>I&#39;m new to Drafts and I have a basic action set up to send a file to a folder in my Dropbox. I&#39;m trying to use it on my Mac but it&#39;s really awkward. I have to use my mouse to go to Actions &gt; Basic &gt; My Action. And that list of actions here is huge. I turned off the visibility of all the actions I don&#39;t care about, but they still show up. So I&#39;d like an easy button or hotkey I could use to run this action on my text. I see that other types of actions are able to be added to the action bar, but basic actions cannot. Is there any way to quickly run a single action from MacOS? Thanks!</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 15:42:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Drafts for Mac</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Easier access to basic actions in MacOS</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[agiletortoise]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Changing the visibility will not “unload” a group, it just affects their availability in the selection menus. If you turn off visibility for the list, the group will no longer be in the dropdown list.</p>
<p>The action bar selector menu (icon to the right) has some caching, it may not <em>immediately</em> fresh the selection when you change the visibility options.</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 15:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-10445-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445.rss">Easier access to basic actions in MacOS</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Easier access to basic actions in MacOS</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[mrdanimal]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks for such a quick response! I’m still having trouble though. I created a Personal group and moved the actions there. I’ve set the group and actions to be visible in the list and action bar. They are visible in the list, but I don’t see them in the action bar. And BTW  if I uncheck the selection for displaying them in the list, they still show up in the list.  And assigning a keyboard shortcut also has no effect. Seems like these settings have no effect. Not sure what I’m doing wrong.</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 16:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-10445-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445.rss">Easier access to basic actions in MacOS</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Easier access to basic actions in MacOS</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[agiletortoise]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The action groups and actions are yours to manage as you see fit. The default set of actions can be a little overwhelming if you have simple use cases, but I suggest the follow:</p>
<ul>
<li>Create a new action group called “Personal”, or whatever, to store your most used actions. <a href="https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/actions/action-groups">Via Manage Actions</a>.</li>
<li>Set this group to be visible in Action List and Action Bar in the visibility settings. This will make it a selectable option in both the list and the action bar.</li>
<li>Move the new dropbox action, and any others you use (Copy, Share, etc.) from other groups to your new group, using right-click “Move” on the actions in the list.</li>
<li>Select the new “Personal” action group in both the list and action bar. This will be remembered, then you have only the items you wish to use regularly visible.</li>
<li>Assign a keyboard shortcut to the action. This is done in the “Keyboard shortcut” section of the action configuration screen. (see <a href="https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/actions/editing-actions">docs</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>Hopefully that helps simplify the experience. As you create/discover new actions you use, you can add them to this group.</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 16:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-10445-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445.rss">Easier access to basic actions in MacOS</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Easier access to basic actions in MacOS</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[mrdanimal]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m new to Drafts and I have a basic action set up to send a file to a folder in my Dropbox. I’m trying to use it on my Mac but it’s really awkward. I have to use my mouse to go to Actions &gt; Basic &gt; My Action. And that list of actions here is huge. I turned off the visibility of all the actions I don’t care about, but they still show up. So I’d like an easy button or hotkey I could use to run this action on my text. I see that other types of actions are able to be added to the action bar, but basic actions cannot. Is there any way to quickly run a single action from MacOS? Thanks!</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 16:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-10445-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/easier-access-to-basic-actions-in-macos/10445.rss">Easier access to basic actions in MacOS</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
