<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Drafts 17 (iOS) Released - Editor improvements, Medium support and more</title>
    <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-17-ios-released-editor-improvements-medium-support-and-more/6365</link>
    <description>Drafts 17 (iOS) has been released [in the App Store](https://itunes.apple.com/app/id1236254471?ls=1&amp;mt=8&amp;at=11l4Cf&amp;ct=site), details below.

_(Also, see [what&#39;s new in the Mac version](https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-17-macos-released-editor-improvements-medium-support-touchbar/6364/2))_

### Editor Improvements

- **Highlight insertion point option to draw different background for current cursor position**.
- **Editor setting to limit max characters per line**. Works along with margin settings to determine a maximum line length. Great for use with full screen mode to prevent excessively long lines.
- New configuration options for visibility of action bar, toolbar and iPad keyboard shortcut bar allowing them to be hidden when editing, or optionally hidden only when external keyboard is connected.
- For more details, see [editor settings docs](https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/editor/editorsettings.html)

### Other Additions

- **App Icon menu options**: The menu displayed when long pressing the app icon on the home screen can now be configured to display recent drafts (the previous behavior), common commands, or workspaces. This setting now defaults to common commands, and can be changed in Settings.
- **Two new monochrome editor themes**. Available to select in `Aa` editor settings.
- **Draft select view updated to allow filtering by workspace**. This view is used in the share extension, iMessages app, and `app.selectDraft()` script interface.
- `Medium` action step type to post to Medium.com. [Docs](https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/actions/steps/services.html#medium)
- `Medium` script object to support scripting Medium API. [Docs](https://scripting.getdrafts.com/classes/medium.html)
- Script steps now have a new &quot;Allow asynchronous execution&quot; option. When enabled, the action will wait for a call to `script.complete()` to know if a script step is finished. This allows use of async/await, Promises and other async function calls...but your script *must* call `script.complete()` of the action will timeout and fail after 60 seconds.
- `CallbackURL` objects have a read-only `url` property to debug the URL which will be used with the configured parameters.

### Other Fixes and Changes

- **Fix:** `Filemanager.readString` would not return undefined properly when file was not found.
- **Fix:** Inaccurate action directory URLs used for opening actions posted to the directory.
- **Fix:** &quot;New draft after&quot; timeout not always working on cold start of the app.
- **Fix:** Issue with action bar visibility on cold start.
- **Fix:** Issue with incorrect syntax highlighting styles when editing drafts with different syntax options in multiple windows on iPadOS.
- Misc. additional fixes and stability improvements.

For a complete history of updates, visit the [changelog](https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/misc/changelog-ios)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 12:17:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>News &amp; Updates</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-17-ios-released-editor-improvements-medium-support-and-more/6365.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Drafts 17 (iOS) Released - Editor improvements, Medium support and more</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[agiletortoise]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Drafts 17 (iOS) has been released <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/app/id1236254471?ls=1&amp;mt=8&amp;at=11l4Cf&amp;ct=site">in the App Store</a>, details below.</p>
<p><em>(Also, see <a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-17-macos-released-editor-improvements-medium-support-touchbar/6364/2">what’s new in the Mac version</a>)</em></p>
<h3>Editor Improvements</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Highlight insertion point option to draw different background for current cursor position</strong>.</li>
<li>
<strong>Editor setting to limit max characters per line</strong>. Works along with margin settings to determine a maximum line length. Great for use with full screen mode to prevent excessively long lines.</li>
<li>New configuration options for visibility of action bar, toolbar and iPad keyboard shortcut bar allowing them to be hidden when editing, or optionally hidden only when external keyboard is connected.</li>
<li>For more details, see <a href="https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/editor/editorsettings.html">editor settings docs</a>
</li>
</ul>
<h3>Other Additions</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>App Icon menu options</strong>: The menu displayed when long pressing the app icon on the home screen can now be configured to display recent drafts (the previous behavior), common commands, or workspaces. This setting now defaults to common commands, and can be changed in Settings.</li>
<li>
<strong>Two new monochrome editor themes</strong>. Available to select in <code>Aa</code> editor settings.</li>
<li>
<strong>Draft select view updated to allow filtering by workspace</strong>. This view is used in the share extension, iMessages app, and <code>app.selectDraft()</code> script interface.</li>
<li>
<code>Medium</code> action step type to post to <a href="http://Medium.com">Medium.com</a>. <a href="https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/actions/steps/services.html#medium">Docs</a>
</li>
<li>
<code>Medium</code> script object to support scripting Medium API. <a href="https://scripting.getdrafts.com/classes/medium.html">Docs</a>
</li>
<li>Script steps now have a new “Allow asynchronous execution” option. When enabled, the action will wait for a call to <code>script.complete()</code> to know if a script step is finished. This allows use of async/await, Promises and other async function calls…but your script <em>must</em> call <code>script.complete()</code> of the action will timeout and fail after 60 seconds.</li>
<li>
<code>CallbackURL</code> objects have a read-only <code>url</code> property to debug the URL which will be used with the configured parameters.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Other Fixes and Changes</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>Fix:</strong> <code>Filemanager.readString</code> would not return undefined properly when file was not found.</li>
<li>
<strong>Fix:</strong> Inaccurate action directory URLs used for opening actions posted to the directory.</li>
<li>
<strong>Fix:</strong> “New draft after” timeout not always working on cold start of the app.</li>
<li>
<strong>Fix:</strong> Issue with action bar visibility on cold start.</li>
<li>
<strong>Fix:</strong> Issue with incorrect syntax highlighting styles when editing drafts with different syntax options in multiple windows on iPadOS.</li>
<li>Misc. additional fixes and stability improvements.</li>
</ul>
<p>For a complete history of updates, visit the <a href="https://docs.getdrafts.com/docs/misc/changelog-ios">changelog</a></p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-17-ios-released-editor-improvements-medium-support-and-more/6365/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-17-ios-released-editor-improvements-medium-support-and-more/6365/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 12:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-6365-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-17-ios-released-editor-improvements-medium-support-and-more/6365.rss">Drafts 17 (iOS) Released - Editor improvements, Medium support and more</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
