<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Need help with ToDoist actions</title>
    <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371</link>
    <description>Hello,

I&#39;m just getting my workflow integrated. Which is another way of saying I don&#39;t have much experience with drafts other than as a way to capture text quickly and efficiently.

I&#39;ve started keeping a log using drafts. My daily log is formatted using markdown like this:
* H1 day and date
* H2 ToDos: a list of all the tasks I accumulate over the day formatted with a dash and then brackets and followed with the actual task
* H2 meeting title or project: with notes from that meant to recall my reaction and/or record what I actually did during the project work

I&#39;d like to process my marked todos into Todoist with an action. I&#39;ve tried various actions from the gallery -- process meeting notes, list unchecked tasks. 

I first I got the satisfying green bar indicating everything worked but no tasks showed up. I check, I tried tests.  Nothing.

So I deleted all the Todoist actions and started again.  Now I don&#39;t even get the satisfying green bar.  

I tested my general ability to run an action -- I&#39;ve moved notes to bar, shared them with the share menu, and sent markdown to devonthink.  

I&#39;m confident that I&#39;m just making a straightforward, simple, and obvious mistake but I can&#39;t figure out what it is.  I&#39;d appreciate any pointers as to what the issue is so that I can resolve it.  

Thanks,
:mw. 

PS -- In case it&#39;s helpful the broader work process I&#39;d like to get to is importing a daily agenda from Fantastical into drafts and then have the note pre-formatted in the way described above.  Then at the end of the day send tasks to ToDoist and send send the notes section to Tinderbox so I can explode them into separate blocks.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 18:41:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Actions - Help &amp; Questions</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Need help with ToDoist actions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[webb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Of course. I should have been clearer. It is <a href="https://actions.getdrafts.com/a/17G" rel="nofollow noopener">the process meeting notes action from the Directory</a>.</p>
<p>;mw</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371/5</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 18:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-8371-5</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371.rss">Need help with ToDoist actions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Need help with ToDoist actions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[agiletortoise]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Could you share your script/action? Very difficult to speculate without specific examples.</p>
<p>Have you read the <a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/using-todoist-with-drafts/1845">Todoist integration guide</a>?  It’s probably the best place to understand the options available. I think the “Tasks in Todoist” example in that guide is probably the best place to start - you would just need to add some logic to identify and route the different custom markup you are using when looping over lines.</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371/4</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 15:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-8371-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371.rss">Need help with ToDoist actions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Need help with ToDoist actions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[webb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thank you for the quick response.</p>
<p>I did catch the space (after a few tries) and have that right in the Drafts note.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Have you also disabled the Things step in the Action as per the action instructions?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I can’t find it. When I go to manage actions -&gt; process meeting notes -&gt; and open the script I only see the ToDoist instructions.  I have removed anything related to things from the actions (using the “-”) in the actions group.</p>
<p>Three other things:</p>
<ol>
<li>I no longer get any signal that the Action has run. No indicator in Drafts (what I get when I run other actions) and it does not show up when I open the Actions Log. Edited to add:  I do get success for processing the action if all items are checked.  If one is unchecked, I don’t get any acknowledgment (not even an error) that the action was run.</li>
<li>I tried – and failed – to find where the actual file is located on my hard drive (versus editing with the built in manage apps work). Maybe that’s what I need to find and how I need to edit the file?</li>
<li>The first time I ran this, I was asked for the ToDoist token. I removed the action (using the “-” in the manage apps).  When I reinstalled from the Directory, I did not get that request for the Token.</li>
</ol>
<p>Thanks again for any help. My next attempt is going to be to delete (again) and then add by copying the script from the directory and treating it as a new action entirely.</p>
<p>Edited to add:  I reinstalled, got the things step tried (a) to comment it out in the manage actions section and (b) to remove.</p>
<p>:mw</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 13:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-8371-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371.rss">Need help with ToDoist actions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Need help with ToDoist actions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[sylumer]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In <a href="https://actions.getdrafts.com/a/17G" rel="nofollow noopener">this process meeting notes action</a>, there is some.codw like this.</p>
<pre><code class="lang-javascript">/* --- Todoist ---*/
let todoist = Todoist.create();
for (var line of lines) {
	if (line.includes("- [ ]")) {
		// Todoist Action
</code></pre>
<p>In the penultimate line of this excerpt you can see what it is looking for to match a Todoist action.  Note the space between the hyphen and the square brackets.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="webb" data-post="1" data-topic="8371">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="https://forums.getdrafts.com/user_avatar/forums.getdrafts.com/webb/40/4069_2.png" class="avatar"> webb:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>a list of all the tasks I accumulate over the day formatted with a dash and then brackets and followed with the actual task</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>You don’t mention anything about the space, so it may well be you are not giving it any matches.</p>
<p>Have you also disabled the Things step in the Action as per the action instructions?</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 05:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-8371-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371.rss">Need help with ToDoist actions</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Need help with ToDoist actions</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[webb]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello,</p>
<p>I’m just getting my workflow integrated. Which is another way of saying I don’t have much experience with drafts other than as a way to capture text quickly and efficiently.</p>
<p>I’ve started keeping a log using drafts. My daily log is formatted using markdown like this:</p>
<ul>
<li>H1 day and date</li>
<li>H2 ToDos: a list of all the tasks I accumulate over the day formatted with a dash and then brackets and followed with the actual task</li>
<li>H2 meeting title or project: with notes from that meant to recall my reaction and/or record what I actually did during the project work</li>
</ul>
<p>I’d like to process my marked todos into Todoist with an action. I’ve tried various actions from the gallery – process meeting notes, list unchecked tasks.</p>
<p>I first I got the satisfying green bar indicating everything worked but no tasks showed up. I check, I tried tests.  Nothing.</p>
<p>So I deleted all the Todoist actions and started again.  Now I don’t even get the satisfying green bar.</p>
<p>I tested my general ability to run an action – I’ve moved notes to bar, shared them with the share menu, and sent markdown to devonthink.</p>
<p>I’m confident that I’m just making a straightforward, simple, and obvious mistake but I can’t figure out what it is.  I’d appreciate any pointers as to what the issue is so that I can resolve it.</p>
<p>Thanks,<br>
:mw.</p>
<p>PS – In case it’s helpful the broader work process I’d like to get to is importing a daily agenda from Fantastical into drafts and then have the note pre-formatted in the way described above.  Then at the end of the day send tasks to ToDoist and send send the notes section to Tinderbox so I can explode them into separate blocks.</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 02:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-8371-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/need-help-with-todoist-actions/8371.rss">Need help with ToDoist actions</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
