<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Drafts as an operating system</title>
    <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275</link>
    <description>Stumbled upon this Alex Cox tweet from yesterday:
https://twitter.com/AlexCox/status/1213217182177517571?s=20

It got me thinking more philosophically about how I use Drafts. Since I&#39;ve been using my iPad Pro and iPhone as my primary computers for over a year (and, yes, I frequently use my iPhone hooked up to an external monitor and a Bluetooth mouse and keyboard), I&#39;ve begun to think of Drafts as my main productivity operating system (built, of course, upon the iOS platform). 

Here are the attributes that allow me to basically treat Drafts like a functional operating system:

- I have a mouse button on my Bluetooth mouse that runs a Shortcut that opens up Drafts to a new draft. I even call the shortcut &quot;Home Page.&quot; 

- Keyboard shortcuts work on both the iPad and iPhone versions of Drafts. That may sound mundane, but it&#39;s not actually true of many iOS apps that have iPhone and iPad counterparts. (To be precise, keyboard shortcuts often work on many apps - including native iOS apps - on the Max and Pro Max phones. They don&#39;t always work with the standard size.) Drafts is one of the few apps that had full support across all device sizes for keyboard shortcuts.    

- Actions, of course! Paired with Shortcuts, I rarely need to actually open other apps to get things done. In fact, for the stuff I use actions for, I could probably reconstruct those entirely within Drafts and forgo Shortcuts altogether. (Even before Drafts for Mac had support for actions, I would actually keep my iPhone in a little stand on my desk and open to Drafts . If I was on my Mac and needed to perform an action, I opened the draft itself on my phone - sync has always been lightning fast for me - and then tapped the action on my phone. Everything synced back to the Mac. It felt like magic.) 

I&#39;ve only been actively using Drafts for a little over a year, so I&#39;m a novice compared to many people here. But it seems to me that the app is so powerful and flexible that treating it like a primary productivity OS could be an interesting approach.

(Disclaimer: I&#39;m not a programmer and do not work in the tech world, so perhaps I&#39;ve mis-used some terms here, like &quot;operating system&quot; and &quot;platform.&quot; Apologies if that&#39;s true.)</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 09:21:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>General Discussion</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Drafts as an operating system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[scripts4drafts]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi, an operating system is a system that operate things.</p>
<p>It’s exactly the way I use Drafts on iOS, ipadOS and macOS through tons of actions ! So yes, for me, Drafts is a real OS that operates text and where action starts.</p>
<p>Heard of interstitial journaling ? Zettelkasten ? It’s all in Drafts and this community helped me a lot to set the system from the one I had beforehand.</p>
<p>The key to use consistently a System is to make it Suited, Simple and Swift (my 4 favorite S :p). Drafts makes it possible : all my actions are customized to my needs and integrated in just 13 buttons above my keyboards. All my drafts (5917 now) are organized within 5 workplaces and 7 tags.</p>
<p>Some actions are simply launching apps and shortcuts, others are navigating through drafts, searching information within drafts, or importing information in the current draft from other drafts, or exporting some information in other drafts or apps, or else parsing some drafts to get a simple or complex analyse. All these actions are executed instantly !</p>
<p>Wow I love this OS <img src="https://forums.getdrafts.com/images/emoji/apple/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275/4</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 09:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-6275-4</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275.rss">Drafts as an operating system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Drafts as an operating system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Chris_Boebel]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>+1 for org mode! Would love to see that!</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275/3</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 22:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-6275-3</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275.rss">Drafts as an operating system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Drafts as an operating system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[elsatch]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I can’t agree more, writing back this replica using my emacs browser! (or Should  I say emacs OS?)</p>
<p>Just kidding! I can see your point on the expandability and lovely customizations you can create from simple pieces.</p>
<p>Best,<br>
César</p>
<p>P.D As I side note, I’m praying for ways to implement emacs org-mode syntax into Drafts. That would be extremely awesome! (Think taskpaper on steroids!)</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 19:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-6275-2</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275.rss">Drafts as an operating system</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Drafts as an operating system</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Econwriter]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Stumbled upon this Alex Cox tweet from yesterday:<br>
</p><aside class="onebox twitterstatus">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://twitter.com/AlexCox/status/1213217182177517571?s=20" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">twitter.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://forums.getdrafts.com/uploads/default/original/2X/8/8785b33d25fa12fdb399b99729ebaebf60f6c39a.jpeg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h4><a href="https://twitter.com/AlexCox/status/1213217182177517571?s=20" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Alex Cox (AlexCox)</a></h4>

<div class="tweet"> Apple Store Employee: "What's your favorite OS?" 

Me: "@draftsapp."</div>

<div class="date">
  <a href="https://twitter.com/AlexCox/status/1213217182177517571?s=20" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">9:54 PM - 3 Jan 2020</a>
    <span class="like">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 512 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M462.3 62.6C407.5 15.9 326 24.3 275.7 76.2L256 96.5l-19.7-20.3C186.1 24.3 104.5 15.9 49.7 62.6c-62.8 53.6-66.1 149.8-9.9 207.9l193.5 199.8c12.5 12.9 32.8 12.9 45.3 0l193.5-199.8c56.3-58.1 53-154.3-9.8-207.9z"></path>
      </svg> 94
    </span>
    <span class="retweet">
      <svg viewBox="0 0 640 512" width="14px" height="16px" aria-hidden="true">
        <path d="M629.657 343.598L528.971 444.284c-9.373 9.372-24.568 9.372-33.941 0L394.343 343.598c-9.373-9.373-9.373-24.569 0-33.941l10.823-10.823c9.562-9.562 25.133-9.34 34.419.492L480 342.118V160H292.451a24.005 24.005 0 0 1-16.971-7.029l-16-16C244.361 121.851 255.069 96 276.451 96H520c13.255 0 24 10.745 24 24v222.118l40.416-42.792c9.285-9.831 24.856-10.054 34.419-.492l10.823 10.823c9.372 9.372 9.372 24.569-.001 33.941zm-265.138 15.431A23.999 23.999 0 0 0 347.548 352H160V169.881l40.416 42.792c9.286 9.831 24.856 10.054 34.419.491l10.822-10.822c9.373-9.373 9.373-24.569 0-33.941L144.971 67.716c-9.373-9.373-24.569-9.373-33.941 0L10.343 168.402c-9.373 9.373-9.373 24.569 0 33.941l10.822 10.822c9.562 9.562 25.133 9.34 34.419-.491L96 169.881V392c0 13.255 10.745 24 24 24h243.549c21.382 0 32.09-25.851 16.971-40.971l-16.001-16z"></path>
      </svg> 5
    </span>
</div>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
<p></p>
<p>It got me thinking more philosophically about how I use Drafts. Since I’ve been using my iPad Pro and iPhone as my primary computers for over a year (and, yes, I frequently use my iPhone hooked up to an external monitor and a Bluetooth mouse and keyboard), I’ve begun to think of Drafts as my main productivity operating system (built, of course, upon the iOS platform).</p>
<p>Here are the attributes that allow me to basically treat Drafts like a functional operating system:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>I have a mouse button on my Bluetooth mouse that runs a Shortcut that opens up Drafts to a new draft. I even call the shortcut “Home Page.”</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Keyboard shortcuts work on both the iPad and iPhone versions of Drafts. That may sound mundane, but it’s not actually true of many iOS apps that have iPhone and iPad counterparts. (To be precise, keyboard shortcuts often work on many apps - including native iOS apps - on the Max and Pro Max phones. They don’t always work with the standard size.) Drafts is one of the few apps that had full support across all device sizes for keyboard shortcuts.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Actions, of course! Paired with Shortcuts, I rarely need to actually open other apps to get things done. In fact, for the stuff I use actions for, I could probably reconstruct those entirely within Drafts and forgo Shortcuts altogether. (Even before Drafts for Mac had support for actions, I would actually keep my iPhone in a little stand on my desk and open to Drafts . If I was on my Mac and needed to perform an action, I opened the draft itself on my phone - sync has always been lightning fast for me - and then tapped the action on my phone. Everything synced back to the Mac. It felt like magic.)</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I’ve only been actively using Drafts for a little over a year, so I’m a novice compared to many people here. But it seems to me that the app is so powerful and flexible that treating it like a primary productivity OS could be an interesting approach.</p>
<p>(Disclaimer: I’m not a programmer and do not work in the tech world, so perhaps I’ve mis-used some terms here, like “operating system” and “platform.” Apologies if that’s true.)</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 17:26:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-6275-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/drafts-as-an-operating-system/6275.rss">Drafts as an operating system</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
