<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Can I &#39;POST&#39; Raw Data to a Web API?</title>
    <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/can-i-post-raw-data-to-a-web-api/8180</link>
    <description>The [`http` class](https://scripting.getdrafts.com/classes/http) looks to have options for encoding the body as `json` or `form`. Is there a way to post as `raw`?

I can specify this in Postman, but without seeing a way to do this from Drafts, all I have so far is being able to get JSON through to the other end, but the entire JSON string is the payload, and I need to send a string that isn&#39;t JSON.

I can split by OS, shelling out to use `curl` on the Mac, and use a Shortcut on i\*OS (setting the body as a file and passing it text for a Get Contents of action seems to work), but I&#39;m thinking that it would be more efficient, at least in terms of simple maintenance, if I can utilise just the native Drafts functionality instead.</description>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 20:03:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Scripting</category>
    <atom:link href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/can-i-post-raw-data-to-a-web-api/8180.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Can I &#39;POST&#39; Raw Data to a Web API?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[sylumer]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The <a href="https://scripting.getdrafts.com/classes/http" rel="nofollow noopener"><code>http</code> class</a> looks to have options for encoding the body as <code>json</code> or <code>form</code>. Is there a way to post as <code>raw</code>?</p>
<p>I can specify this in Postman, but without seeing a way to do this from Drafts, all I have so far is being able to get JSON through to the other end, but the entire JSON string is the payload, and I need to send a string that isn’t JSON.</p>
<p>I can split by OS, shelling out to use <code>curl</code> on the Mac, and use a Shortcut on i*OS (setting the body as a file and passing it text for a Get Contents of action seems to work), but I’m thinking that it would be more efficient, at least in terms of simple maintenance, if I can utilise just the native Drafts functionality instead.</p>
          <p><a href="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/can-i-post-raw-data-to-a-web-api/8180/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/can-i-post-raw-data-to-a-web-api/8180/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 20:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.getdrafts.com-post-8180-1</guid>
        <source url="https://forums.getdrafts.com/t/can-i-post-raw-data-to-a-web-api/8180.rss">Can I &#39;POST&#39; Raw Data to a Web API?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
